Ruth Wudu Tadese

(901) 335-1621 | ruthwudu576@gmail.com | LinkedIn <u>linkedin.com/in/ruth-w-tadese-54118925</u> | Richmond, VA

SUMMARY

Experience developing Java web applications. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel in Java based applications in AWS cloud environment as well as highlight my previous experience and leadership abilities. Extensive customer handling and correspondence experience in supply chain and International Import/Export industry. Multilingual.

SKILLS

Java, HTML, CSS, IntelliJ idea, GitHub, OOP, REST API, Heroku, CL, Agile, Scrum, Bootstrap, Spring Boot, Virtualization, Amazon EC2, Auto Scaling, Load Balancing, Networking, AWS Calculation, Amazon S3, Precise, coordinating, Data handling.

EDUCATION

Junior Full Stack Java Web development | Generation USA | Mar 2022 – July 2022 AWS Cloud Practitioner | Utah Refugee Center, Salt Lake City, Utah | April 2021 – Feb 2022 Java Web Development | Montgomery College, Rockville, MD | Jun 2021 – Aug 2021 Bachelor's in Business Management | Zegha Business College | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia | Jan 2006 – March 2010

PROJECT

Timesheet Approval Workflow | https://quiet-mesa-37070.herokuapp.com/

Used Java, Spring MVC, JDBC and rest web services to develop the backend and HTML, CSS and Bootstrap for frontend development. Implemented spring security and maven dependency for artifacts handling.

EXPERIENCE

Supply Chain Coordinator | Unicorn Tire Corporation, Memphis, TN | Sept 2018 – Jul 2019

• Coordinated shipments imported from China to the US and maintained customer data and prepared freight invoices using different databases.

Import/Export Manager | Dragon Woodland Sawmill Corporation, Memphis, TN | Nov 2017 - Sept 2018

Handled export shipments from US to China. Negotiated freight rates, tracked and tranced status
of containers.

International Sales Officer | OTC Global GmbH, Berlin, Germany | July 2016 - Apr 2017

Assisted on the company's website development project and handled international import/export.

Container Follow-up Officer, Europe Trade Route Coordinator & Junior Logistics Officer | June 2010 – June 2014

Ethiopian Shipping & Logistics Services Enterprise, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Handled and followed up shipments coming from different countries through multimodal transportation.
- Mentored 4 junior logistics officers. Corresponded with customers, trucking companies and regulatory offices.